Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP Turkish, Bulgarian

DRIVER'S LICENCE B Class

DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH 28th January 1987, Bulgaria

EDUCATION

2005 – 2017 Architecture (B.Arch.)

Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul

2001 – 2005 High School (Science and Math)

Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School,

Bursa

CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

TALKS GIVEN

Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design
 ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
 Prototyping & Optimizing Game Asset Workflow
 Blender Conference, Amsterdam
 Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender

Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig

2014 Blender Python Programming Workshop BlendFX Studios, Leipzig

2011 **AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop**ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul

PARTICIPATION

2015 Game Developers Conference EU 2015 (Cologne)

UBM Tech

2014 Blender Conference (Amsterdam)
Blender Foundation

2014 Libre Graphics Meeting (Leipzig)
LGM Crew

2014 Blender Python Workshop (Leipzig) Kenan Bölükbaşı

2011 **IAF Compositing Workshop (İstanbul)** Özgür Gülbir

WORK EXPERIENCE

6x13 Games, İstanbul

JAN 2015 - [CONT'D]

Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Game design, development, project management, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the globally featured free to play symmetrical movement puzzle.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES.
 4 free to play handheld console games. The titles are:

- 1FPS: INVADERS - 1FPS: VACUUM

- 1FPS: VACUUM - 1FPS: FASTFOOD

- 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project, FAÇADE, at ITU. It generates facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Invited industry participant at some Architectural Design Computing Master's Program classes at ITU.

EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL AUG 2013 – JAN 2015

Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game assets.

FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

Jun 2011 - Feb 2014

Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 – SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President İlham Aliyev's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

SosyalMedya.CO, İstanbul

FEB 2011 - MAR 2012

Author

Tech industry reports. Column in monthly e-journal. Interview with former Turkey & MEA Marketing Manager of Google.

EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Event Supervisor

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

Aşçıoğlu İnşaat, İstanbul

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

ALPO ENGINEERING, İSTANBUL

Mar 2007 – May 2007

3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games 2017

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured in the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories as well as the AppStore Turkey homepage. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games 4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

Hy Programming Language Blender Integration 2013 Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

2012

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

2011 **TwitGraph**

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

DESIGN PROJECTS

- 2016 ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos 2014 Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest. Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Cankaya Ulvi Cemal Erkin Concert Hall & Cultural Center Architectural Design Competition Participation (with Gülsev Özbelen & Gizem Kaya)
- **Nooka International Watch Design Competition** 2010 Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design
- 2009 **Akçansa Concrete Ideas Competition** Finalist (with Büşra Atabek)

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

ENGLISH

- Listening: C2 (Mastery)* Reading: C2 (Mastery)*
- Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)* Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)*
- Writing: C2 (Mastery)*
- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing - ITU Research Paper Writing - ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties.

Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP clients including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

Azerbaijani

- Listening: B2 (Upper intermediate)* Reading: B1 (Intermediate)*
- A2 (Elementary)*
- A1 (Beginner)*
- · Work experience for a month in Baku. Several organizations with Azerbaijani clients.

TURKISH

- · Native Speaker
- (*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

SOFTWARE SKILLS

GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

00000	Blender 3D	þ
00000	Inkscape	
0000	ImageMagick, FFMpeg	
00000	GIMP, Photoshop	
	3D Studio Max, Maya	
00000	BI & Cycles Renderers	
0000	Luxrender, Yafaray	
00000	AutoCAD, DraftSight	
	Luminance HDR	

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

0000	C / C++	
00000	Common Lisp, Scheme	Y
00000	Python, Factor	Y
00000	UNIX / Shell	
	Lua, HTML5	

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

00000	Emacs	h
0000	Visual Studio	
0000	GCC, Clang, MSBuild	
0000	GDB, LLDB, Valgrind	
	Make, CMake, Gradle	AC.
00000	Git Version Control System	AC.
00000	Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++)	þ
	Xcode, Android Studio	

OPERATING SYSTEMS

00000	GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian)	y
00000	Windows XP/7/8/10	₽ ^C
	macOS	₽ ^C

DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

Co

00000	T _E X / L ^A T _E X Systems	
00000	Org-Mode, Markdown	₽ ^C
00000	Doxygen, Pandoc	
0000	MS Office, Libre Office, Scribus	

Additional Information

Hobbies	Walking, Computer Science, Technology Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing
OMMUNITIES	Free / Libre & Open Source Software, Blender Network, Lisp Game Development

Factor Language Development